Guide to the Jerome Moross Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Works by Jerome Moross
  - Subseries III.84: Symphony No 1
    - Publicity: periodicals. 1) "Modern Music," Vol. 22, No. 2. Jan.-Feb. 1945. (p. 111-114.) 2) "Rob Wagner's Script," Vol. 30, No. 693. Dec. 2, 1944. (p. 24). 3) Photocopies of articles., 1944-1945, (1 vol., 1 vol., 4 pages) (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous publicity: 1) Statement. 2) Guggenheim Fellowship application., 1944, n.d., (1 page, 2 pages) (Box 36)
    - Score for two pianos "Second Movement Sonata Scherzo": manuscript on thin sheets, signed., 1943, (21 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 37)
    - Score for two pianos: 1) Ozalid copy; p. 8-28. 2) "Second Movement": ozalid copy; p. 9-28. 1943, (21 pages, 20 pages) (Box 37)
    - Score for two pianos "IV-Fugue": ozalid copy; p. 34-42., 1943, (9 pages) (Box 37)
    - Tape recording of radio broadcast: "Symphony No. 1: L.A. Philharmonic-Wallenstein.", 19 Nov 1944, (1 cassette) (Box 41)
    - Records: Los Angeles Philharmonic, Alfred Wallenstein, conductor. 1) "Symphony No. 1," 4 copies. 2) "Symphony No. 1, 3rd and 4th Movements" and "1st and End mvts." 3) "Symphony #1, First Movement.", (4 discs, 1 disc, 1 disc) (Box 43)
    - Orchestral Score (30 parts): new master parts with all corrections., 1943, (220 pages, 3 folders) (Box 46)
    - Piano score: new master part with all corrections., 1943, (15 pages) (Box 46)
    - Recording: compact disc. London Symphony Orchestra, JoAnn Falletta conductor., London, 1993, (1 disc) (Box 46)
      [Gift 1993. With "The Last Judgement" and "Variations on a Waltz."]
    - 1) Orchestral score: photocopy with composer's corrections. 2) List of movements and instruments specific to performance the Seattle Symphony Orchestra (WA)., 18 Oct 1943, (146 pages, 1 page) (Box 254)
    - 1) Orchestral score: manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) Composers notes on reduced copy of score., 1943, (146 pages a.ms.s., 2 pages) (Box 254)
    - Orchestral score: ozalid copy., 1943, (146 pages bd.) (Box 254)
  - Subseries III.85: Symphony No 2
    - Score: manuscript sketches., (95 pages) (Box 37)
    - Score: manuscript sketches, signed., (5 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 37)
  - Subseries III.86: Tall Story for Orchestra
    - 1) Programs. 2) Orchestral score: reduced ozalid negatives., 1938, (14 items, 96 pages) (Box 37)
    - Parts (27): manuscript on transparencies. 1938, (149 pages) (Box 37)
    - 1) Orchestral score: manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) List of players., 1938, (96 pages a.ms., 1 page t.ms.) (Box 255)
  - Subseries III.87: There's a Moon Tonight
    - Announcement/ticket., (1 item) (Box 37)
  - Subseries III.88: Those Everlasting Blues
    - Orchestral score: manuscript, signed., 1932, (27 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 37)
    - 1) Program: New School for Social Research (NY). 2) Newspaper clippings including New York Sun, 29 Oct 1932., 1932, (1 item, 2 pages) (Box 37)
  - Subseries III.89: Those Gamblers' Blues
    - Vocal score: ozalid copy., (6 pages ) (Box 37)
  - Subseries III.90: Tumwater Rhapsody
    Olympia Beer Commercial.
    - Orchestral score: ozalid negatives., 1966, (55 pages) (Box 37)
    - Piano score "Theme from Tumwater Music": 1) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) Ozalid copy; 2 copies of 2 p., 1966, (2 pages a.ms.s., 4 pages) (Box 37)
    - Score: ozalid copy., 1966, (55 pages bd.) (Box 255)
  - Subseries III.91: Two Songs
    "Jabberwocky" and "Those Gamblers Blues."
    - 1) Program: The New School Auditorium (NY). 2) Newspaper clipping., 1933, (2 items, 1 page) (Box 37)
  - Subseries III.92: Underworld
    - Playscript: 1) Mimeograph copy. 2) Mimeograph copy., 1960, (111 pages, 110 pages) (Box 37)
    - Playscript: miscellaneous pages with notes added in pencil., 1960, (43 pages t.ms.) (Box 37)
    - Playscript: draft, carbon copy; two copies of 60 pages., 1960, (120 pages) (Box 37)
    - Playscript: miscellaneous xerox pages., 1960, (52 pages t.ms.) (Box 37)
    - Vocal score "Baby's Gonna Shake It Tonight" (song): 1) Manuscript, signed. 2) Ozalid copy., 1960, (7 pages a.ms., 7 pages) (Box 38)
    - "The Bad Old Days" (song). 1) Lyrics. Vocal score: 1) Manuscript, signed. 3) Manuscript, signed. 4) Ozalid copies with changes; two copies of 4 p., 1960, (1 page, 6 pages a.ms.s., 4 pages a.ms.s., 8 pages) (Box 38)
    - "Beer and Flowers" (song). Vocal score: manuscript, signed., 1960, (9 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 38)
    - Vocal score "The Cream of Society" (song): 1) Manuscript, signed. 2) Ozalid copy with pencil changes. 3) Ozalid copy; 3 copies of 9 p., 1960, (9 pages a.ms.s., 9 pages, 27 pages) (Box 38)
    - "Danger" (song): 1) Lyrics with changes in pencil. Vocal score: 2) Manuscript on thin sheets in pencil, signed. 3) Ozalid copy with pencil changes; two copies of 6 p., bd. 4) Manuscript on thin sheets in pencil, signed. 5) Photocopy. "Cicero's Danger Song." Vocal score: 6) Manuscript on thin sheets in pencil with ozalid copy; two copies of 8 p., 1960, (1 page t.ms., 3 pages a.ms.s., 2 vol., 11 pages a.ms.s., 11 pages, 16 pages) (Box 38)
    - "The Girls" (song): 1) Lyrics with pencil changes. 2) Vocal score: manuscript on thin sheets., 1960, (5 pages t.ms., 5 pages a.ms.) (Box 38)
    - Vocal score "Give Me a Chance" (song): 1) Manuscript on thin sheets with pencil changes; signed. 2) Ozalid copy with pencil changes; three copies of 6 p. 3) Ozalid copy., 1960, (6 pages a.ms.s., 18 pages, 6 pages) (Box 38)
    - Vocal score "It's Almost Time Now" (song): 1) Manuscript, signed. 2) Ozalid copy with pencil notes., 1960, (5 pages, 5 pages) (Box 38)
    - Vocal score "I've Even Been in Love" (song): 1) Manuscript, signed. 2) Ozalid copy with pencil notes; 2 copies of 11 p. 3) Ozalid copy., 1960, (11 pages a.ms.s., 22 pages, 11 pages) (Box 38)
    - "Keep on Saying It" (song). Score: 1) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed. Vocal score: 2) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 3) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed., 1960, (6 pages a.ms.s., 6 pages a.ms.s., 4 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 38)
    - "Kinda Like" (song). 1) Lyrics. Score: 2) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed;. 3) Manuscript sketch., 1960, (2 pages, 5 pages a.ms.s., 1 page a.ms.) (Box 38)
    - Vocal score "Love Me" (song): 1) Manuscript, signed. 2) Ozalid copy with pencil changes. 3) Ozalid copy., 1960, (6 pages a.ms.s., 6 pages, 6 pages) (Box 38)
    - Vocal score "Paddy Boy" (song): manuscript on thin sheets, signed., 1960, (9 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 38)
    - Score "Pepita's Song" (song): manucript on thin pages., 1960, (7 pages a.ms.) (Box 38)
    - "Prologue" (song). 1) Lyrics. 2) Score: manuscript on thin sheets. Vocal score: 3) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 4) Ozalid copy., 1960, (3 pages t.ms., 6 pages a.ms., 6 pages a.ms., 6 pages) (Box 38)
    - Vocal score "That Extra Bit" (song): 1) Manuscript, signed. 2) Ozalid copy., 1960, (8 pages a.ms.s., 8 pages) (Box 38)
    - "You've Got Brains" (song). 1) Score: manuscript, signed. 2) Vocal score: manuscript, signed., 1960, (6 pages a.ms.s., 2 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous items. Scores: 1) Manuscript sketches; 2 p. Lyrics, t.ms.: 2) "All I Have Left," carbon copy; 1 p., t.ms. 3) "Chicago Isn't Mine Anymore," with pencil changes; 3 p. 4) "Fighting and Drinking"; 4 p., t.ms. 5) "Make It a Fast One"; 2 p., a.ms. 6) "Mock Wedding" carbon copy; 2 p., t.ms. 7) "Start It Moving"; 4 p., a. and t.ms. 8) "We're Throwing a Party" carbon copy; 1 p., t.ms., 1960, (17 pages ms.) (Box 38)
    - Compact disc: "Songs from the Underworld" and "Parade." Broadway soundtrack., 1991, (1 disc) (Box 47)
    - Vocal scores: ozalid copies with pencil changes. 1) "Beer and Flowers"; 9 p. 2) "Keep on Saying It"; 4 p. 3) "Paddy Boy"; 9 p. 4) "Prologue and Epilogue"; 6 p. 5) "That Extra Bit"; 8 p. 6) "You Got Brains"; 2 p. 7) "You Got Brains (Tango)"; 2 p., 1960, (7 folios, 40 pages) (Box 255)
  - Subseries III.93: V-Day
    Script by Arch Oboler
    - 1) Playscript: mimeograph copy with pencil changes. 2) Score: ozalid copy., 27 June 1943, (21 pages, 3 pages) (Box 38)
  - Subseries III.94: Valley of Gwangi
    - Score: manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 1968, (164 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 38)
    - Score: ozalid copy. 1968, (164 pages bd.) (Box 38)
    - Compact disc: "The Classic Film Music of Jerome Moross." City of Prague Philharmonic conducted by Paul Bateman. Includes: "The Valley of Gwangi," "The Sharkfighters," "Rachel, Rachel," "The War Lord," "The Mountain Road," "Five Finger Exercise," "Wagon Train," and "The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn.", 1995 copyright, (1 disc) (Box 47)
  - Subseries III.95: Variations
    - Program: The New Chamber Orchestra., Town Hall, 113 West 43rd St., New York City., 3 December 1933, (4 items) (Box 38)
  - Subseries III.96: Variations on a Waltz
    See also compact disc: Symphony No. 1.(Box 46)
    - Score (31 Parts): manuscript on transparencies in copyist's hand., 1980, (259 pages ms.) (Box 38)
      [Orchestral work]
    - Record. "Variations on a Waltz: Two Piano Demo.", (1 disc) (Box 43)
    - 1) Orchestral score: manuscript on thin sheets; signed. 2) List of players., 1980, (156 pages a.ms.s., 1 page t.ms.) (Box 255)
  - Subseries III.97: Wagons Ho!
    - Theme music: published score in vol.; p. 62-64, 1959, (3 pages bd.) (Box 39)
      [Television show]
  - Subseries III.98: Warlord
    - Conductor parts: 2 ozalid copies of 128 p., 1965, (256 pages) (Box 39)
    - Conductor parts: Ozalid copy with recording history. 1965, (128 pages bd.) (Box 39)
    - Record. "The War Lord: Original Soundtrack Album.", 1965, (1 disc) (Box 43)
    - Conductor score: manuscript; signed. 1) 1A: "Prelude"; 4 p. -- 2) 1C: "Main Title"; 7 p. -- 3) Reel 2, Cue B: "Pagan Shrine"; 3 p. -- 4) Reel II, Part C: "Forsaken Village"; 4 p. -- 5) Reel II, Part D and Reel II Part A: "Obsession Begins"; 8 p. -- 6) Reel III, Part B: "Father's Fate"; 3 p. -- 7) 3C: "The Hunt"; 1 p. -- 8) 3D: "Naked Emotion"; 6 p. -- 9) 4A: "To Ease the Pain"; 9 p. -- 10) 4B: "Agony Shared"; 2 p. -- 11) 4C: "Injured Dignity"; 3 p. -- 12) 4D-5A: "Witch Chase"; 4 p. -- 13) 5B: "Come Lie with Me"; 6 p. -- 14) 5C: "Judge and Jury"; 2 p. -- 15) 5D: "Consent to Wed"; 5 p. -- 15) Reel VI, Part A: "Rustic Wedding"; 5 p. -- 16) 6B: "Marriage Ceremony and Dance"; 6 p. -- 17) 7A: "Virgin Sacrifice"; 6 p. -- 18) 7B: "Bewitched"; 5 p. -- 19) 7C-8A: "Vigil in the Night"; 1 p. -- 20) 8B: "Pledge at Dawn"; 6 p. -- 21) 9B: "What of the Future"; 11 p. -- 22) 13C-14A: "Vengeance and Death"; 10 p. -- 23) 14B: "End Title"; 2 p., 1965, (23 folios, 128 pages) (Box 256)
    - Orchestral score: thermofax copy. 1965, (17 pages) (Box 256)
  - Subseries III.99: When I Grow Up
    - 1) Score: manuscript, signed. -- 2) Payment receipts., 1951, (82 pages a.ms.s., 2 pages) (Box 39)
    - Video tape recording: "When I Grow Up.", 1951, (1 cassette) (Box 41)
  - Subseries III.100: World Turned Upside Down
    Based upon a Revolutionary War tune played at the surrender of Cornwallis.
    - 1) Score: manuscript in pencil, signed. 2) Photocopy from "The Music of George Washington's Time," p. 36-37., (6 pages a.ms.s., 1 page) (Box 39)
  - Subseries III.101: Would-Be Gentleman
    Music adapted from J.B. Lully
    - 1) Contract (Moross/William Morris Agency, Inc.). 2) Program (Booth Theatre, NY). Scores:manuscripts on thin sheets. 3) "Finale Act I"; 2 p. 4) "Final Minuet-Finale Act II"; 2 p. 5) "Madame Jourdains Exit"; 1 p. 6) "Overture"; 3 p. 7) "Pas de Trois"; 5 p. 8) "Serenade"; 2 p. 9) "Stop Thief"; 1 p. 10) "Turkish March"; 1 p. 11) "Werner's Specialty"; 7 p. 12) "Werner's Specialty"; 2 p. 13) "Pas de Trois," score for five parts in copyist's hand; 18 p. 14) "Pas de Trois," ozalid copy; 5 p. 15) Miscellaneous. Ozalid copy; 1 p. 1945, (2 items, 50 pages) (Box 39)
- SeriesIV: Miscellaneous items
  - Subseries IV.1: Lyrics
    - "All She Knew How to Do was the Tango.", (1 page) (Box 39)
  - Subseries IV.2: Outline for Operetta
    - "The Marriage of Lorenzo.", (1 page) (Box 39)
  - Subseries IV.3: Score
    - Untitled manuscript sketch: "Page 9.", (1 page) (Box 39)